Finding Aid for Theodore Souris papers, 1946-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Theodore Souris papers 1946-1968 1960-1968
Souris, Theodore, 1925-
89290 Aa 2
Michigan Supreme Court justice; court files, 1960-1968, clippings, 1960 campaign materials, audio-tapes, and photographs; also University of Michigan student notebooks on courses in history and economics taught by Dwight L. Dumond, Howard M. Ehrmann, William Haber, Lewis G. Vander Velde, and William B. Willcox.
34 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The bulk of this collection (donor no. 2341 ) came to the library in August of 1991.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Theodore Souris was born August 5, 1925 in Detroit, Michigan. He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1947, and from the University of Michigan Law School in 1949. He practiced law in Detroit from 1949 to 1959 at which time he was appointed by Governor G. Mennen Williams to the Wayne Circuit Court. On January 5, 1960, Williams appointed him to the Michigan Supreme Court. He was elected to the court in November of 1960 and served until December 31, 1967. He died June 21, 2002.
The Souris papers, except for a few volumes of student notebooks from his classes at the University of Michigan, consist of files maintained as a Michigan Supreme Court Justice. As the collection only recently opened to research, there is at present only box level control of the contents of the collection.
Subjects:
Dumond, Dwight Lowell, 1895-1976; Ehrmann, Howard M. (Howard Meredith), 1898-1989; Elections--Michigan--1960.; Haber, William, 1899-1988.; Michigan. Supreme Court.; Souris, Theodore, 1925-; University of Michigan--Student notebooks.; Vander Velde, Lewis G. (Lewis George), 1890-1975.; Willcox, William B., 1907-1985
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Judges--Michigan.; Souris, Theodore, 1925-
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.
- Court files
  This series is largely unprocessed.
  - Index To Cases, 3 volumes (Box 1)
  - Alphabetical files January 1960-July 1968
    - A (Box 1)
    - A-B (Box 2)
    - B-C (Box 3)
    - C (Box 4)
    - C-D (Box 5)
    - D-F (Box 6)
    - F-G (Box 7)
    - G-H (Box 8)
    - H-I (Box 9)
    - I-K (Box 10)
    - K-L (Box 11)
    - L-M (Box 12)
    - M (Box 13)
    - N-P (Box 14)
    - P (Box 15)
    - P-R (Box 16)
    - R-S (Box 17)
    - S (Box 18)
    - S-T (Box 19)
    - T-W (Box 20)
    - W-Z (Box 21)
  - Speeches/articles (Box 21)
  - Conference schedules (Box 22)
  - Window Matters (petition for appeal) adopted
    - 1/60-10/61 (Box 22)
    - 11/61-10/63 (Box 23)
    - 10/63-9/64 (Box 24)
    - 10/64-4/65 (Box 25)
    - 5/65-7/66 (Box 26)
    - 8/66-5/67 (Box 27)
    - 6/67-4/68 (Box 28)
    - 5/68-7/68 (Box 29)
  - Published court dockets (Box 29)
- Other materials
  - Clipping files 1959-1967 (Box 30)
  - 1960 campaign materials (Box 31)
  - 1960 campaign materials (Box 32)
    (continued)
  - 1968 campaign materials, 1967-1968, 4 folders (Box 33)
  - University of Michigan class notebooks on courses taught by Dwight L. Dumond, Howard M. Ehrmann, William Haber, Lewis G. Vander Velde, and William B. Willcox 1946-1947, 6 volumes (Box 33)
  - Audio-tapes of speeches
    (compact disc use copies have been made of the tapes
    - Le Billet de Loterie 007 and Les Deux Peches (Box 33)
    - The Rule of Law (Box 33)
    - Law #3 (Box 33)
    - Law #4 (Box 33)
    - Souris Interview Part 1, April 3, 1965 (Box 33)
    - Souris Interview Part 2, April 3, 1965 (Box 33)
    - Dissent and the Law January 17, 1968 (Box 33)
      (appearance of Judge Souris on WJR Radio
  - Motion picture film (unidentified) (Box 33)
    (DVD copy available)
  - CD of Talk (circa 55 minutes), 1 optical disks CDs (Box 33)
  - Photographs, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 34)